

Michael Panco Frontend Web Developer / Fullstack Developer

+639682305982 / +639776336055 micpanco@gmail.com Cainta Rizal, Philippines

A resourceful, self-motivated, talented web developer with over **14 years of working experience** in delivering web projects to a high standard. I have a proven track record of providing delightful UI design, accurate details, and effective user experience. I am dedicated to driving innovation with the ability to follow industry and technological trends and facilitate early adaptation of innovations.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Frontend Developer

Sept 2022 – Sept 2024 / 2 Yrs

Trainalta / Encora

- Developed interactive timetable for client's gym profile programs.
- Enhance the gym page user interface to make it more appealing.
- Led the successful development of the Earnportal with the latest NextJS.
- Collaborated with other developers, designers, and project teams to ensure a successful result

Fullstack Web Developer

Nov 2021 - Aug 2022 / 1 Yr

Vokke / GetDevs

- Refactored existing applications, cutting development time by 30% while ensuring performance standings.
- Led the successful frontend development from start to finish
- Improved user experience resulting in customer satisfaction.
- Collaborated with other developers, designers, and project teams to ensure a successful result

Freelance Web Developer

Jan 2020 - Oct 2021 / 1.8 Yrs

Property Investment Inc.

- Developed the product CRM, and introduced all the cutting-edge tools to make the project compete with product competitors.
- Integrate marketing tools to track user product engagement.
- Contribute ideas especially on UI and UX to make it more appealing for t and easy to use.

Senior Web Developer

Sep 2015 - Dec 2019 / 4 Yrs

Bizme Solutions

- Pioneered the overall project classesa2z.com from managing the server, building the user interface, and backend creation.
- Mentored 3 junior developers in software development processes.
- Facilitated integration of third-party services like Stripe and other APIs to satisfy customer's needs.
- Communicate with the project owner to ensure the functionalities are adequately adapted.

Web Developer Software Developer Junior Web Developer Bona88 Casino Mobile Ventures Inc. PH Offshore Inc. Jan 2015 – Jul 2015 Jun 2012 – Dec 2014 Jan 2010 – May 2012

SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

- Javascript / Typescript
- React / NextJS
- Redux / Redux Saga
- HTML / CSS
- React Native
- PHP / Laravel
- Strapi / Contentful
- MaterialUI / Tailwind / ShadCN UI
- NodeJS / ExpressJS / NestJS
- Figma Design Conversion
- Mobile-first Development Practices
- Algolia / Elasticsearch
- Adobe Photoshop
- GIT
- Web Performance Optimization
- Agile and Scrum

SOFT SKILLS

- Teamwork
- Works well under pressure
- Willingness to try new things
- Learning agility
- Resilience
- Problem Solving
- Creativity

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science – 2009 Navotas Polytechnic College, Navotas City, Philippines

PERSONAL DETAILS

Gender: Male

Date of Birth: June 26, 1988

Civil Status: Married